This video is sponsored by DeleteMe. I
love science fiction.
I love the idea of exploring space, of
discovering strange new worlds, of
building cool spaceships, and of
settling in places other than Earth.
When I was a kid, I was watching this
series called Space: 1999. It was
basically a British Star Trek knockoff.
This is what we had on TV, okay? The
series tells the story of Moonbase Alpha
in a world where a massive explosion
caused the moon to break away from
Earth's orbit, hurtling into deep space,
bringing Moonbase Alpha with it. And as
the moon penetrates deeper and deeper
into space, including via a couple of
wormholes, the staff of Moonbase Alpha
must contend with various challenges,
meeting new alien races, encountering
exotic phenomena, strange new worlds,
all that. Except the USS Enterprise is a
heavenly body. I loved the idea of
Moonbase Alpha. I loved the idea of
space colonies in general. This is why,
when I heard Elon Musk talk about
wanting to colonize the moon, I was
like, "What? Are you mental?" A
moon colony? You want to live on the
moon? And let's just put aside
the fact that Musk had been promising a
Mars colony for a decade, saying how he
would land a human on Mars 2 years ago.
And now, [music] 10 years after the
original promise, this giga genius
realized that, actually,
the moon
is closer.
Oh my god, Elon Musk. How does he do it?
How does he do it? How does he do it?
Okay, I guess we're doing a moon colony
now. Let's just forget about the decade
of constant promises about the Mars
colony. To the moon, then. It's going to
be great. As long as your definition of
great is a horrifying disaster in every
way imaginable. Why? Let's take a look.
But first, here's a footprint. It's on
the moon, as opposed to yours, which is
on the internet. How about you reduce it
by getting rid of all the personal data
floating around there? Sounds good?
Well, now you can easily do that with
today's sponsor, DeleteMe. The internet
is becoming increasingly predatory.
Companies like Palantir, not to mention
all the AI algorithms are all looking to
scrape your data. This data is used to
find you down algorithms, help surveil
you, and of course make money off you,
like those dynamic Walmart price tags.
Oh, look, it's John, and he just got a
pay raise at work. So, let's jack up the
prices in each aisle he walks around in.
But, having a bunch of sensitive data
out there also leaves you vulnerable to
identity theft, harassment, and more.
This is why you should keep your digital
footprint under control by removing
superfluous personal data from the
internet. And you can do that with
DeleteMe. DeleteMe helps remove your
personal data by scanning hundreds of
data broker websites that collect your
online personal data. Experts at
DeleteMe will then request its removal,
helping you reduce your digital
footprint. A week later, you get a
privacy report telling you what data was
found and removed. DeleteMe will rescan
those websites later to make sure that
the data is gone for good. Do not let
your personal data fall into the wrong
hands. Get 20% off DeleteMe consumer
plans by going to
joindeleteme.com/adam20
and use the promo code Adam20 during
checkout. That's
joindeleteme.com/adam20,
promo code Adam20. Thank you for
checking out DeleteMe. Now, back to the
moon. Contrary to popular belief, the
moon is a hellscape. It's actually worse
and more dangerous than Mars. So,
really, a Mars colony would make more
sense than a moon colony, save for the
distance. For example, Mars at least has
this thing called atmosphere. It's a
very thin atmosphere, but hey, at least
it's [music] there. The moon has no
atmosphere, which means on the surface
you're in constant danger of
micrometeorites, tiny rocks from space
that are coming at you at the speed of a
bullet. All it takes is one unlucky hit
and you're done. Now, this is not a
problem if you only have a couple of
dudes spending a few hours or days on
the surface and then pack their stuff
and go back to Earth. But, if you have
thousands of people out on the surface
every day, you'll start having problems.
Even more so with a big, wide, sprawling
structure sitting around on the surface.
If a bigger micro meteorite hits your
habitat and demolishes a wall or a
window, everyone in that habitat will be
dead, including Mr. Galaxy Brain. Um uh
actually, we will um design an energy
barrier that will
>> Shut up, Radar. Go back to your forks.
But micrometeorites are not the only
things falling on you. Since there is no
atmosphere or magnetosphere, that means
exposure to unfiltered solar and cosmic
radiation. Great. I always like the idea
of damage to my DNA. Or getting cancer,
or electronics randomly crap out because
cosmic rays hit them the wrong way. On
the moon, any and all unshielded
electronics would be toast pretty much
immediately. So, Elon Musk is standing
on the moon dodging micrometeorites
while baking in hazardous amounts of
radiation. He's trying to post a tweet,
but his phone gets fried by a solar
flare. Oh my god, the
the juice broke my phone. And he will be
standing there either in a temperature
of plus 121° C
or minus 133
because the moon is incapable of
trapping heat because it has no
atmosphere. Some areas are even more
extreme. Inside craters where there is
permanent darkness, temperatures can be
as low as minus 246°
C.
So, if you walk down from the sunny edge
into the crater, well, let's just hope
that your equipment can handle a
temperature swing of 367°
in a matter of seconds. And each day on
the moon lasts about 2 weeks. So, it's 2
weeks of bright infernal heat versus 2
weeks of pitch-black icy hell. How do
you store your energy? How do you make
sure that your batteries survive the
temperature swings? What if you run out
of energy in the middle of the
2-week-long night? How do you protect
structures and equipment from material
fatigue owing to extreme heat expansion
and contraction, or micrometeorites for
that matter? Any problem, any hiccup,
any oversight, or unexpected failure can
cost people's lives and or put the
entire mission at risk. Of course, these
bases come with fail-safes, fail-safes
to those fail-safes, and fail-safes to
those fail-safes. Normally. However,
this moon colony would be built by Elon
Musk, the man who designed a truck in
which the accelerator pedal's cover is
prone to come off because they just
glued it there. And when it comes off,
it becomes a wedge holding down the
pedal causing the car to accelerate
indefinitely. Contrary to the rest of
the Tesla models, the Cybertruck was
developed under the direct control of
Musk, and oh boy, did it turn out well.
And now, after revolutionizing pickup
trucks, this guy wants to build a moon
colony. But even if the colony is built
by actually competent people, the
surface of the moon is a complete
non-starter. Any surface moon base will
be constantly bombarded by meteorites,
fried by radiation, boiled by the sun,
or frozen in the dark. How do you solve
this problem? Well, one way to do so is
to go underground. All right, everyone,
welcome to the moon. Let us proceed to
our brand new moon colony. It's just
over there, at the bottom of that cave.
Yep, that's right. Your lay epic future
420 Marvel Keanu Reeves cyberpunk moon
colony would mean life in a windowless
bunker inside a cave, with most of your
time awake spent maintaining the
equipment keeping you alive. And even if
you do happen to have some free time,
what will you even do? Oh, I know. How
about some online gaming? Yeah, just
chilling. How about some Path of Exile
2, Elon? Oh my god, if you haven't heard
of this, you're missing out. In 2025,
Elon Musk decided to show off his
incredible gaming skills. At he was the
global number one Diablo 4 player, a
feat that requires incredible amounts of
time spent grinding for items and
leveling up. Becoming global number one
is basically a full-time job, requiring
40-plus hours of play each week,
possibly more. How this giga genius
could accomplish this feat while
simultaneously being Tesla CEO, SpaceX
chief engineer, Doge director, and
Donald Trump's
>> [clears throat]
>> first buddy is just mysterious as it is
incredible, especially when you consider
that Diablo 4 is not the only game in
which he excelled. In January 2025, Elon
Musk decided to stream a now infamous
gameplay of Path of Exile 2, a game very
similar to Diablo 4. And apparently, he
made it to the global top in this game
as well. His character,
>> [gasps]
>> Cackius Maximus, being global rank 59
[music] out of 14 million players.
Needless to say, getting to this rank
also requires a full-time job's worth of
time every week. Musk said his account
wasn't boosted. That's when you pay
someone else to play and grind instead
of you. He insisted that it was he alone
who managed to achieve that rank owing
to his incredible gaming skills. But
then, he started playing. By meditation,
meditation before battle is always good.
And he starts killing monsters. He
starts obliterating monsters with his
character. And but what becomes uh
obviously apparent
Chaos orb, no loot filter. He's like not
He's just running past chaos orbs. He's
just RUNNING PAST THE CHAOS ORBS. CHAOS
ORBS are one of the most important
currencies, and they're also really
rare. I have about 140 exalt. I had like
nine chaos orbs. Just so you guys
understand. At one point, he opens his
equipment screen revealing the best gear
in the entire game. The Path of Exile
community was looking at his screen
collectively salivating at the sight of
what is basically the holy grail of the
game. And then Elon is like, So uh
I know. All right, I'm like
level 95, but my staff is only level 62.
So I haven't been able to find a better
staff.
You know.
Yeah, that chest is kind of mid. My I
got casters and 1.6 k evasion.
LIKE
UH OH, WAIT. THIS ONE'S HYBRID
[screaming]
WITH A ASH. ARE YOU KIDDING ME, BRO?
WHAT THE
OH MY GOD, THIS ONE'S like twice as good
as mine.
At least a level 75 jacket.
Yeah, level 52 here.
The conclusion of this beautiful
disaster was Musk giving streaming
another go, silently playing on his
private jet via Starlink. While people
spammed insults at him on the chat,
visible to the public on his stream,
because he doesn't know how to turn off
private messages.
>> [music]
>> I would like to remind everyone that
this man claims to be able to build a
base on the moon. Anyway, on the
moon he wouldn't be able to do this.
Latency is 1,300 milliseconds, and that
is something not even Starlink can fix,
since it's due to the moon being 384,000
km away. And otherwise, what really is
there to do on the moon, for humans
anyway? Why should human beings have a
permanent presence there? And by that, I
don't mean a small scientific outpost
like the ISS. No, I mean what Elon Musk
means when he talks about a moon colony.
A permanent human settlement in which
people live. Which, I should add, is the
thing that generates all the hype around
Elon Musk's idea. People are not excited
about ISS on the moon. No, people, and
mostly venture capitalists, are excited
about cities on the moon. Which is a
dangerous, stupid, and generally
horrible idea for all the reasons we've
discussed so far. But also because of
things like low gravity, which is about
1/6 compared to Earth. And this is kind
of a problem, since the fact that we
live in 1G just happens to be absolutely
fundamental to our survival. For
example, the astronauts on the ISS
experience accelerated bone loss at an
alarming rate, about 12 times faster
than severe osteoporosis on Earth. It
basically dissolves your bones. Look, as
things stand right now, humans are just
not built to withstand environments
other than Earth. Maybe in the perhaps
not so distant future, when we'll be
able to have fully synthetic bodies or
something, like in Ghost in the Shell,
that would kind of work. And it would be
awesome. Oh, hey, how's that development
going, Elon?
Oh.
And with that, thank you for watching,
and I'll be seeing you next time.
>> [music]